var:
A value in JavaScript is always of a certain type. For example, a string or a number.
There are eight basic data types in JavaScript.

Number;
let n = 123;
n = 12.345;
The number type represents both integer and floating point numbers.
There are many operations for numbers, e.g. multiplication *, division /, addition +, subtraction -, and so on.
Besides regular numbers, there are so-called “special numeric values” which also belong to this data type: Infinity, -Infinity and NaN.
Infinity represents the mathematical Infinity ∞. It is a special value that’s greater than any number.
We can get it as a result of division by zero:
alert( 1 / 0 ); // Infinity
Or just reference it directly:
alert( Infinity ); // Infinity
NaN represents a computational error. It is a result of an incorrect or an undefined mathematical operation, for instance:
alert( "not a number" / 2 ); // NaN, such division is erroneous
NaN is sticky. Any further operation on NaN returns NaN:
alert( "not a number" / 2 + 5 ); // NaN
So, if there’s a NaN somewhere in a mathematical expression, it propagates to the whole result.
In JavaScript, the “number” type cannot represent integer values larger than (253-1) (that’s 9007199254740991), or less than -(-253-1) for negatives. 
It’s a technical limitation caused by their internal representation.

String
A string in JavaScript must be surrounded by quotes.

let str = "Hello";
let str2 = 'Single quotes are ok too';
let phrase = `can embed another ${str}`;
In JavaScript, there are 3 types of quotes.

Double quotes: "Hello".
Single quotes: 'Hello'.
Backticks: `Hello`.
Double and single quotes are “simple” quotes. There’s practically no difference between them in JavaScript.

Boolean (logical type)
The boolean type has only two values: true and false.

This type is commonly used to store yes/no values: true means “yes, correct”, and false means “no, incorrect”.

For instance:

let nameFieldChecked = true; // yes, name field is checked
let ageFieldChecked = false; // no, age field is not checked
Boolean values also come as a result of comparisons:

let isGreater = 4 > 1;

alert( isGreater ); // true (the comparison result is "yes")

The “null” value
The special null value does not belong to any of the types described above.

It forms a separate type of its own which contains only the null value:

let age = null;
In JavaScript, null is not a “reference to a non-existing object” or a “null pointer” like in some other languages.

It’s just a special value which represents “nothing”, “empty” or “value unknown”.

The code above states that age is unknown.

The “undefined” value

The special value undefined also stands apart. It makes a type of its own, just like null.

The meaning of undefined is “value is not assigned”.

If a variable is declared, but not assigned, then its value is undefined:

let age;

alert(age); // shows "undefined"
Technically, it is possible to explicitly assign undefined to a variable:

let age = 100;

// change the value to undefined
age = undefined;

alert(age); // "undefined"
…But we don’t recommend doing that. 
Normally, one uses null to assign an “empty” or “unknown” value to a variable, while undefined is reserved as a default initial value for unassigned things.

Objects and Symbols
The object type is special.

All other types are called “primitive” because their values can contain only a single thing (be it a string or a number or whatever). 
In contrast, objects are used to store collections of data and more complex entities.

Being that important, objects deserve a special treatment. 
We’ll deal with them later in the chapter Objects, after we learn more about primitives.
The typeof operator
The typeof operator returns the type of the argument. It’s useful when we want to process values of different types differently or just want to do a quick check.

It supports two forms of syntax:

As an operator: typeof x.
As a function: typeof(x).
In other words, it works with parentheses or without them. The result is the same.

The call to typeof x returns a string with the type name:
typeof undefined // "undefined"
typeof 0 // "number"
typeof 10n // "bigint"
typeof true // "boolean"
typeof "foo" // "string"
typeof Symbol("id") // "symbol"
The symbol type is used to create unique identifiers for objects. We have to mention it here for the sake of completeness, but also postpone the details till we know objects.